so there's business voice in the back of
my head that keeps saying this is not a
technology cooperative it's not a
technology company it's not technology
and yet all I've been saying I mean I've
been saying it for a reason because
before it was this is a technology
cooperative now all of a sudden it's
like this is not a technology
cooperative part of that I understand
what it is and I am resisting it because
it is the piece that is not the product
not the process it is the individual
piece of how I got here it is creating a
culture and a system of learning which
means not shame culture but growth
culture what happened what went wrong
doing things out in the open and
learning from them and that is very much
intimately intertwined with the mission
of together tech but there's a piece of
like self-reflection and growth that you
have to do to be kind of be able to get
there and this this cultural of radical
acceptance we're like you might not see
this person as as good as you as but
like they are they are just as worthy as
you even if you can't see it and often
we're not gonna be able to see it you're
worthy exactly as you are and so there's
that piece and I'm I'm eventually gonna
get to and it's gonna be released and
we'll see we'll see how that goes so
that there's that piece that is my own
inter in piece of like right this isn't
a technology for me I don't only have
technology to give there's this other
piece of me I have to give that is
equally as powerful but aside from that
there's a huge people keep bringing up
technology because it's a technology
cooperative and there's something that
like grates at me when that happens I'm
like but we're not the same as them and
part of that I have to own it I have and
like meditating through it I'm sure
there's more to it to come but it wasn't
that it was like right cuz you're not
explaining it well and you're right it's
not a technology company like what makes
us different than them is there a
technology company and we're not what we
are is a solutions cooperative a way to
create solutions together in this space
between I have to do it all on my own
and they will fix it
how do we bring people together to
create solutions together and a lot of
those those others the github and open
source do create solutions together but
they're not designed to create solutions
together they're a technology company
that creates solutions together and we
are a solutions company and it creates
technology so that means we're not
designed for the technologically elite
we're not designed for the to make a
profit
we're designed for the purpose of making
our members lives better and how we do
that is by listening to our members and
not on I'm we are gonna listen to our
members but on a like I'm a member
you're a member we need to find our
common problems and solve them together
and empowered with the tools to be able
to make that easier and easier and
looking at the system what's working for
me and not working for me what would
make this more powerful for me what
would make this easier for me so the
system of creating a solution and I need
to honor that I also had a conversation
with Heather we talked about how
solution is the wrong word and I agree
it is a very game a word it had craze
with it a lot of baggage of like we've
solved it check and there is no solution
like that these are constant sorry
iterations on you start with something
that's good enough
Bittan created openly and transparently
and you keep on making it better with a
culture of learning growth what went
wrong
how could we have how could we have
improve that if we knew what we knew now
and then how do we do do that in the
future every time something goes wrong
we're looking for things that could go
wrong and hopefully you know stopping
them before they go wrong but when they
go wrong we look at what happened
without blame and shame and correct them
and fix them and if different solutions
work for different people we're creating
a solution together so we don't want you
to leave and create your own because
that's gonna actually hurt the solution
itself 10,000 of us recreating a food
solution for our city is gonna be more
powerful than to 5,000 genes with their
you know purchasing power to 5000 teams
might create something to compete me
like yours is better and jump on board
but there's gonna be a cost to
dissipating energy and I saw I was just
talkin on the last videos it kind of
will be into it what we are creating is
solutions and so that is partly we are
talking about this fix the world
Friday's is micro solidarity and that
process which to me is very much the the
I to the them the like I need to solve
it by myself which I can't do and they
need to solve it for us we need to pass
laws they need you like enforce those
laws those companies need to do what
what we're paying them not to do like
the system needs to be different and I'm
not I it's too much for me because I
can't how does one person have power so
there's that space in between which is
where we're creating solutions it's not
hopefully demanding other people have to
have our solution it's inviting them to
be part of creating one that works for
all of us because we want all of us and
so what you can't do is demand that
other people use it the same way you do
right because that's gonna dissipate it
you have to be this category to be here
is gonna dissipate the energy but that's
like a hole in the radio so what we are
creating what's together tech is the
solutions cooperative but we need to
have eventually a better word than
solutions problem-solving brainstorming
like a system to improve our lives
together every we need a new word
because every word is gonna have you
like a sentence that I need to say we
need to say so join us on fix the world
Friday we're gonna talk solutions and
micro solidarity and creating creating
technology that saves the world whatever
just technology it's the system it's the
connection it's the conversations and
the infrastructure that supports that
that is what we were doing together
thank you